Hi friends, today we will look at ICICI LBD.
ICICI LBD is a general insurance company
whose Q1 earnings have come.  It has arrived on 15th July
and we are analyzing it on 16th.
So,
we will see what is inside it within two to three minutes and
according to us, their Q1 earnings report has
been good and the stock may be
seen running today.  But it is not a
recommendation.  You can keep an eye on this and
keep it on the watchlist.  Let's start friends.
In their statement, we will talk about crores
and will first look at the total income.
So, you can see that the
total income in the present quarter is Rs 683 crore,
which was Rs 5,851 crore in the last quarter.
So, if we look at the growth of 5851 in the last quarter from
quarter to quarter, then we
can almost say that
we are
seeing a growth of 20 to 25% from quarter to quarter.   That
is, from 5851 crores to 683 crores.  Now if we
look at it on a quarterly basis, it is
coming to Rs 5351 crore.  So it is 53 51 crores and
here it is 6883 crores, if we see it point wise then
and eight, then here we can say that you are seeing a growth of 20% to 25% on
Y basis, the
total income i.e. revenue wise is
seen increasing both quarter to quarter and year to year, according to which we
can say that this is a good growth
revenue wise to be seen here and if we
look at their income, that this is an insurance company
and this is a medical insurance company,
here we will see gross
premium,
net premium, premium ended, income from
the investment
and other income.  Income is obtained by adding all these.  You
can see the rest of the details later.   If we
look at the total expenses, the total expenses
that are coming out now are
around Rs 5429 crores.  So, against Rs
5429 crore, the expenditure in the last quarter was Rs
5435 crore.  So 5435 crores
and 29 crores, so 29 crores, the expenses are a little less than this, we
can also say this from the previous quarter that as
our sales are increasing, the
expenses are decreasing accordingly, so
quarter to quarter your profit will be good,
operating profit will be good, if we
look at it in terms of Q1 2024, then the
expenses for these two Q1 2024 are coming to 4850 crores.
Expenses seem to be coming down from here too.
Now let us see
what their profit is coming out to be.
So we will see their profit, underwriting
profit.  If you look at the underwriting profit, that
is, after subtracting your expenses from the income, your
underwriting profit is
coming to approximately ₹93 crores.
How much was it in the last quarter?   It was worth
approximately ₹9 crore.  Well,
how much was Quarter One in 2024?  It was worth around Rs 3.46
crore.  So if you look at it that way,
you are seeing growth quarter to quarter.
From Rs 209 crore to Rs 293 crore and there is
not that much growth on the basis of the previous quarter.
From Rs 446 crore to Rs 293 crore, here we can
say that a loss of Rs 40 to 50 crore is
visible here
in underwriting profit.
Talking about operating profit, the
operating profit
is also coming to around Rs 654 crore.
What was the operating profit in the last quarter?  If we
can say 515 crores, then from 515 crores to 655 crores, a
growth of approximately 40% is being seen.  If
seen on end year basis, it
was 501 crores and 654 crores, so here also see,
150 crores means there seems to be a profit.
So here also, a growth of about 30% is
visible in your operating profit on a direct and continuous basis.  And
in Y24 and Y25 it is
seen on YQ1 basis and YQ1 on 25 basis.   If we
talk about profit after tax PAT,
what is their PAT?  PAT is
coming to around Rs 747 crore in the present quarter,
which used to be Rs 59 crore in the last quarter
and in its previous quarter
i.e. Q1 24, it was Rs 580 crore.
So here, if we look at the jump on Q1 basis, then we
can approximately say that a benefit of around Rs 150 crore is being
seen.  150 crores,
benefits of more than 150 crores are being seen.
So if you calculate this percentage roughly, then
you are seeing a growth of around 25% or more in PAT of around Rs 454 crore.
Where in quarter to quarter, from
quarter one to quarter one 24
quarter one 25, we will call it 26
but I am assuming it to be 25 only.
According to the results of quarter one 25, if we
look at quarter four
from quarter four, then we will look at quarter two 24 from
quarter one 25, then the results are from
509 crores to 447 crores, so
roughly speaking, a difference of 20 crores to 250 crores was
seen, so here we can say
that you are seeing a growth of almost above 50-40%,
that is, your PAT is
increasing by 40%, how is it increasing on both the basis,
quarterly and yearly basis,
so this is a strong growth being
seen from both the points of view, if we look at the
bottom line growth in ICICI LBD in this stock, then
what is the EPS growth coming?
EPS growth in this present quarter,
after the
exceptional items, we will count the
basic EPS of 15.06.  Q1 Q4 24
how much EPS is 10.29.
So here we can say that
you can directly see the growth of 50% in EPS along with the profit.  The
denominator used to be your
EPS of 11.68.  Your EPS is 11.68
in quarter one, quarter one 24, if we
look at it quarter to quarter yearly, our EPS is coming to around 15.
So here we can say that you are seeing 40%
EPS growth on such quarter to
quarter yearly basis.  So
EPS growth
is visible from both points of view.  If we look at EPS on FI basis also, it is
coming to 50.  So we
cannot compress FI that much right now.  FI
25 is the data of 24.  So here you will see that there is
data of 25.  50 is an EPS of 50.  So here we will
see that we are seeing continuous growth in EPS.
Since it is an insurance
sector, the solvency ratio in it is one.  If we
look at the solvency ratio,
currently your solvency ratio is
2.70.  Look at the last quarter it was
2.67.  Its previous one was 2.56.
So your solvency ratio also
seems to be improving.  Then expense of
management ratio.  How much is the management
spending?  Is 27.8.  See,
the expense of management
ratio should be reduced and yours is 32.8 in the last quarter.
26.8 is coming.  So keep continuing and
you will see improvement.  It is being found that
this should be less in the expense of management ratio.
So it is less than the last quarter.
But here you will see that the ear in
appears to be slightly enlarged.  It is
seen increasing by one point i.e. 26.8 or 27.8.
Management expenses
seem to be increasing.  We
will look at the debt claim ratio.
Then if we look at the combined ratio of SSL Roberts, the
combined ratio is 102.9, 102.5,
102.6, so the combined ratio
seems to be going above 100, which can be said to be a
matter of concern.  Here the
combined ratio should have been below 100.  If you
look at the earnings,
I have already told you about the shares per earning.  And NPA
population,
see their yield.  If we look at the yield of investment, it is
2.32 without unutilized.  It was
2.62 in the last quarter.  Its
previous yearly basis was 2.21.  So
from here, improvement in yield is
visible in both the positions.  This thing is
proving to be okay.  If we
look at the yield as per end with unutilized gain, it was 3.60
, 2.17, 3.20.
Improvement is visible in the yield here also.  Then
public holding number of shares.  Public
holding
percentage wise will see the percentage
of the holding.  If we look at the public holding, it is
48.54.  It is 48.40.  Is 48.19.   The
public holds 40% shareholding here.   Take a look at
them segment wise.  Asia LBD which is
an insurance company is
working in which segment.  So as you
can see here, look at them segment wise, they are
working in fire.  Insurance is being
provided there.  Marine is seen paying the insurance tax.  It is providing
health insurance
for personal accidents and health group
and corporate insurance.  The
government is giving health to business.
Where is their money coming from, Wise?
Where is the maximum penetration?  So
look at the fire, now look at the profit loss, 5000 is
about 54 54 crores.  They seem to be suffering losses here in Marin.
29 crores in this present quarter.  Look, if we
look at it from the perspective of health and personal accident insurance, your health will come to retail
, group and government.
See all this here segment
wise
underwriting profit loss is showing loss
in the present quarter.
So overall, Lambert is a life
insurance company.  It is a medical insurance
company and works in all types of segments.
So their top line bottom line
growth of 20 to 40% is being seen.
EPS growth is also being seen.
But some ratios can be consistent with this.
So these days you can keep an eye on it and
keep it in your watch list.  But
it is not a recommendation.  You can see this.
This performance can be
good today.  Thank you friends.
See you in the next video.
Bye till then.